<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Data Science Portfolio on Jay Guwalani</title>
    <link>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Data Science Portfolio on Jay Guwalani</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-1 : E-commerce Shipping</title>
      <link>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Aim of the Project : To build an End-to-End Web App using Data Science &amp;amp; Machine Learning for an International E-commerce Company to predict whether their products will reach on committed Delivery Time or not.
Life Cycle of the Project :
Collected the dataset from Kaggle Preprocessed the data well and built an ML model by tuning the Hyperparameters of Random-Forest Classifier using Randomized-Search-CV Saved the Best Performing model in a Pickle file Built a Web App using Python at the Backend with Flask API and HTML &amp;amp; Bootstrap serving at the Frontend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-2: Face-Mask-Detection</title>
      <link>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Aim of the Project
To build a Web App using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks to predict whether a person is Wearing a Mask or Not
Life Cycle of the Project
Collected the dataset from Kaggle which contained 12,000 images in total for both the classes Used Data Augmentation to generate extra data from the existing dataset Applied Transfer Learning using Pre-trained VGG16 model and built a High Performance Custom CNN Model providing an Accuracy of 99.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-3: Customer Churn Prediction</title>
      <link>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Aim of the Project : To predict, analyze and provide the counter measures to prevent the customers&amp;rsquo; from Churning. Build a Model to predict the Customers&amp;rsquo; likely to be churned using Data Science, and Machine Learning Applications.
Business Understanding : The data used to build a Customer Churn Prediction Model, consists of data related Telecom domain, and their behavioral trends w.r.t. Churning across 4 years of time span.
Life Cycle of the Project: Extracted the data from Kaggle open source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-4: Risk-Analytics-Fraud-Detection</title>
      <link>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Aim of the Project
To predict and analyze the fraudulent transactions that happen on daily basis, using Credit cards. Provide countermeasures for the same. Build a Model to prevent such transactions using Data Science, and Machine Learning Applications.
Life Cycle of the Project
Extracted the data from Kaggle open source. Performed Data Exploration to understand the descriptive stats w.r.t. the data, in order to manipulate the data to build a robust ML model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-5: Spam Detection</title>
      <link>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Aim of the Project
To predict, analyze and provide the counter measures to prevent the Spamming. Build a Model to predict the Spam Messages&amp;rsquo; likely to be churned using Data Science, NLP and Machine Learning Applications.
Life Cycle of the Project
Extracted the data from Kaggle open source. Performed Data Exploration to understand the descriptive stats w.r.t. the data, in order to manipulate the data to build a robust ML model.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Project-6: Breast-Cancer Wisconsin Diagnostic</title>
      <link>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Aim of the Project
Predict if the patients have Breast Cancer or not. And also classify that it is Malignant / Benign using UCI dataset
Life Cycle of the Project
Collected the dataset from Kaggle open source. Performed Data Cleaning using Pandas and Seaborn. Used Pandas, matplotlib &amp;amp; Numpy for Data Pre-processing, to decrease the redundancy, by taking care of the missing values, and duplicates. Used Label Encoder to handle the imbalanced dataset, in order to avoid the OVERFITTING.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jayds22.github.io/Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can contact me here:
   Platform URL     G-Mail: Jay Guwalani - Gmail   GitHub: https://github.com/JayDS22   LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jay-guwalani-66763b191/   Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/jayds22   Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/jay___20_4/    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>